<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>deep-learning on Biologically Plausible Programming</title>
    <link>/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in deep-learning on Biologically Plausible Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch Dataset Class: Simply Elegant</title>
      <link>/22/02/2021/pytorch-dataset-class-simply-elegant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/22/02/2021/pytorch-dataset-class-simply-elegant/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Over the past few weeks, I have been experimenting with and learning more about the popular PyTorch (torch) package that like Keras and Tensorflow, provides an easy way to implement deep learning algorithms. In this post, I show why I think torch&amp;rsquo;s Dataset class is an elegant and beginner-friendly way to handle the process of data processing. As I have written previously, it&amp;rsquo;s more important to ensure you have the correct data than actually implementing a target model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing Loss: Lessons From a Summer of Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/14/09/2020/minimizing-loss-lessons-from-a-summer-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/14/09/2020/minimizing-loss-lessons-from-a-summer-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
While there is debate on how much similar deep learning(DL) operations are to the corresponding brain computations, these operations have been applied to several problems often generating excitement and sometimes unwarranted hype. Of all the DL applications, image processing has considerably matured and provided better results compared to traditional processes that relied on simple(r) kernel convolutions.
For the biomedical community, the UNet algorithm proposed by Ronneberger et al.(2015) has successfully been applied to several problems ranging from basic segmentation tasks to more complex tasks like cell tracking and cell cycle progress monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
