<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Biologically Plausible Programming</title>
    <link>/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Biologically Plausible Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing loss: Lessons from a Summer of Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/14/09/2020/minimizing-loss-lessons-from-a-summer-of-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/14/09/2020/minimizing-loss-lessons-from-a-summer-of-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
While there is debate on how much similar deep learning(DL) operations are to the corresponding brain computaions, these operations have been applied to several problems often generating excitement and sometimes unwarranted hype. Of all the DL applications, image processing has considerably matured and provided better results compared to traditional processes that relied on &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo;(r) kernel convolutions.
For the biomedical community, the Unet algorithm proposed by Ronneberger et al.(2015) has succesfully been applied to several problems ranging from basic segmentation tasks to more complex tasks like cell tracking and cell cycle progress monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a custom Kaggle Favicon to Hugo&#39;s Blackburn Theme</title>
      <link>/07/05/2020/how-to-add-a-custom-kaggle-favicon-to-hugo-s-blackburn-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/07/05/2020/how-to-add-a-custom-kaggle-favicon-to-hugo-s-blackburn-theme/</guid>
      <description>In this short article, I show how I added a Kaggle favicon to the site.
Prerequisites:
R packages
  magrittr
  magick
  Why did I need to create a custom favicon?
I admittedly do not use Kaggle as much as I used to a year or so ago, mainly because I&amp;rsquo;ve found the site to be less enjoyable but that&amp;rsquo;s a post for another day.
The real reason for the need to create a custom icon was the desire to include Kaggle under the side bar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>