<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r on Biologically Plausible Programming</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r on Biologically Plausible Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Software: The Case for Student Involvement</title>
      <link>/blogs/open-source-student-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/open-source-student-involvement/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
For over two years now, I have devoted most of my time to either building open source software or alerting developers of issues with &amp;ldquo;their&amp;rdquo; software. I use their in quotes because open source software really is community software and most developers have the community&amp;rsquo;s needs first.
During this time, I have grown a lot as a developer and believe that most of this growth has come from my involvement with developer communities be it over at StackOverflow or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Loops for the Python Programmer</title>
      <link>/blogs/2020-07-21-r-loops-for-the-python-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 23:35:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/2020-07-21-r-loops-for-the-python-programmer/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Whenever possible use vectorised alternatives instead of loops, seq_along and 1:length will be handy when looping through data.
The R vs Python debate is one that has stood the test of time. Thousands of articles and tweets have been made that aim to argue for the use of one language over another. Fortunately for the reader, this post is not aimed at justifying the use of one language.
On the contrary, as someone who is fairly proficient in both languages, I thought it would be nice to write about key differences between loops in R and python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Hexagon sticker with R in Minutes</title>
      <link>/blogs/hex-sticker-creation-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/hex-sticker-creation-r/</guid>
      <description>I have recently released new versions of manymodelr and mde, R packages you may or may not have heard of.
One common feature of many R packages is a hexagon shaped sticker that often summarises the goals of the package and/or gives an idea of the developer’s philosophy. I am, as those who know me well might tell you, not the best of artists. I however, have always marveled at these beautiful stickers in others’ packages and wished to create one myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a custom Kaggle Favicon to Hugo&#39;s Blackburn Theme</title>
      <link>/blogs/how-to-add-a-custom-kaggle-favicon-to-hugo-s-blackburn-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/how-to-add-a-custom-kaggle-favicon-to-hugo-s-blackburn-theme/</guid>
      <description>In this short article, I show how I added a Kaggle favicon to the site.
Prerequisites:
R packages
  magrittr
  magick
  Why did I need to create a custom favicon?
I admittedly do not use Kaggle as much as I used to a year or so ago, mainly because I&amp;rsquo;ve found the site to be less enjoyable but that&amp;rsquo;s a post for another day.
The real reason for the need to create a custom icon was the desire to include Kaggle under the side bar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
