<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Automate the Data Exploration Pipeline</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Automate the Data Exploration Pipeline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a custom Kaggle Favicon to Hugo&#39;s Blackburn Theme</title>
      <link>/07/05/2020/how-to-add-a-custom-kaggle-favicon-to-hugo-s-blackburn-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/07/05/2020/how-to-add-a-custom-kaggle-favicon-to-hugo-s-blackburn-theme/</guid>
      <description>In this short article, I show how I added a Kaggle favicon to the site.
Prerequisites:
R packages
  magrittr
  magick
  Why did I need to create a custom favicon?
I admittedly do not use Kaggle as much as I used to a year or so ago, mainly because I&amp;rsquo;ve found the site to be less enjoyable as it used to be but that&amp;rsquo;s a post for another day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>manymodelr: Build and Tune Several Models</title>
      <link>/07/05/2020/manymodelr-build-and-tune-several-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/07/05/2020/manymodelr-build-and-tune-several-models/</guid>
      <description>manymodelr: Build and Tune Several Models
In this vignette, we take a look at how we can simplify many machine learning tasks using manymodelr. We will take a look at the core functions first.
Installing the package
install.packages(&amp;quot;manymodelr&amp;quot;)Once the package has been successfully installed, we can then proceed by loading the package and exploring some of the key functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Data Explorer</title>
      <link>/07/05/2020/missing-data-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/07/05/2020/missing-data-explorer/</guid>
      <description>This is the development version of mde. The acronym mde stands for Missing Data Explorer, a package that is intended to make missing data exploration as smooth and easy as possible.
The goal of mde is to ease exploration of missingness without feeling overwhelmed by syntax with particular focus on simplicity.
Installation
CRAN releaseinstall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>