<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-source on Biologically Plausible Programming</title>
    <link>/categories/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open-source on Biologically Plausible Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin Classes for the Python Developer</title>
      <link>/07/07/2022/simple-look-at-kotlin-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/07/07/2022/simple-look-at-kotlin-classes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For anyone who has followed the tech scene and/or Android Development for some time, Kotlin, a language developed at JetBrains is likely familiar. The language has also received a lot of media attention as the future of Android development, receiving backing from tech giant, Google.
To understand why this is the case, I have recently started learning Kotlin mainly for fun and to see how well the language lives up to its hype (praise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequel to Pandas</title>
      <link>/05/03/2022/sql-to-python-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/05/03/2022/sql-to-python-pandas/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important parts of the data analysis pipeline is the ability to collate data obtained from different sources. While the CSV file format remains the most popular form of data input, a lot of times production level data analysis requires that one fetch data from an internet source which in the simplest form may involve downloading a CSV file from a remote source. Often, however, the data fetch process requires interaction with a database which therefore necessitates that one have an understanding of relational databases and how to interact with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing big by building small.</title>
      <link>/17/03/2021/small-projects-not-so-small-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17/03/2021/small-projects-not-so-small-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Why build when you can simply read?
The importance of learning as one builds has been echoed so many times in the open-source development world that another article on the same might seem not worth the time. However, our experiences are unique and offer a unique perspective even on topics that may have been read and written about countless times.
When a problem sparks an idea
A month or so ago, I was ready to submit updates to the R packages manymodelr and mde and thought the process would go just as smooth as it always does, if you ignore the usual issues with fixing tests and unidentified bugs that is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
