<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github on Biologically Plausible Programming</title>
    <link>/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on Biologically Plausible Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo, Blogdown, and Github: What could go wrong?</title>
      <link>/25/12/2020/hugo-blogdown-pitfalls-to-avoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/25/12/2020/hugo-blogdown-pitfalls-to-avoid/</guid>
      <description>One of the most beautiful things about open source development is the idea that one picks up crucial skills like versioning be it via git* or any version control system of their choosing. For non developers, such versioning can be accomplished via syncing files to the cloud or manually uploading files each time. Alternatively, and in the most extreme scenario, one could simply version their files by simple file number incrementation: file_1_edit, file_1_edit_final, file_1_edit_final_final_finally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Software: The Case for Student Involvement</title>
      <link>/06/10/2020/open-source-student-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/06/10/2020/open-source-student-involvement/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
For over two years now, I have devoted most of my time to either building open source software or alerting developers of issues with &amp;ldquo;their&amp;rdquo; software. I use their in quotes because open source software really is community software and most developers have the community&amp;rsquo;s needs first.
During this time, I have grown a lot as a developer and believe that most of this growth has come from my involvement with developer communities be it over at StackOverflow or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
