<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-source on Biologically Plausible Programming</title>
    <link>/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open-source on Biologically Plausible Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Growing big by building small.</title>
      <link>/17/03/2021/small-projects-not-so-small-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17/03/2021/small-projects-not-so-small-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Why build when you can simply read?
The importance of learning as one builds has been echoed so many times in the open-source development world that another article on the same might seem not worth the time. However, our experiences are unique and offer a unique perspective even on topics that may have been read and written about countless times.
When a problem sparks an idea
A month or so ago, I was ready to submit updates to the R packages manymodelr and mde and thought the process would go just as smooth as it always does, if you ignore the usual issues with fixing tests and unidentified bugs that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch Dataset Class: Simply Elegant</title>
      <link>/22/02/2021/pytorch-dataset-class-simply-elegant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/22/02/2021/pytorch-dataset-class-simply-elegant/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Over the past few weeks, I have been experimenting with and learning more about the popular PyTorch (torch) package that like Keras and Tensorflow, provides an easy way to implement deep learning algorithms. In this post, I show why I think torch&amp;rsquo;s Dataset class is an elegant and beginner-friendly way to handle the process of data processing. As I have written previously, it&amp;rsquo;s more important to ensure you have the correct data than actually implementing a target model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo, Blogdown, and Github: What could go wrong?</title>
      <link>/25/12/2020/hugo-blogdown-pitfalls-to-avoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/25/12/2020/hugo-blogdown-pitfalls-to-avoid/</guid>
      <description>One of the most beautiful things about open source development is the idea that one picks up crucial skills like versioning be it via git* or any version control system of their choosing. For non developers, such versioning can be accomplished via syncing files to the cloud or manually uploading files each time. Alternatively, and in the most extreme scenario, one could simply version their files by simple file number incrementation: file_1_edit, file_1_edit_final, file_1_edit_final_final_finally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Software: The Case for Student Involvement</title>
      <link>/06/10/2020/open-source-student-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/06/10/2020/open-source-student-involvement/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
For over two years now, I have devoted most of my time to either building open source software or alerting developers of issues with &amp;ldquo;their&amp;rdquo; software. I use their in quotes because open source software really is community software and most developers have the community&amp;rsquo;s needs first.
During this time, I have grown a lot as a developer and believe that most of this growth has come from my involvement with developer communities be it over at StackOverflow or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
